So now we're going to get some practice on Amazon bedrock and the first thing
I want you to do if you want to follow along is to switch the region and to go to
US east Northern Virginia which is US east one. The reason why I want to be there for
the whole course is that the availability of some AI services is restricted to
some regions for now and so being in US east one will guarantee that you will be
able to access all the services you need. Okay so now that we're good let's go
into the search bar and let's tap Amazon bedrock. Next we're going to click on
get started and we are into the Amazon bedrock UI. So let's close this and
we're going to explore together. So here we go so we are in the overview and the
first thing I want to show you is the providers list on the left hand side. So
we have to choose a foundation model to get started with generated AI and we
can choose the foundation model from many different types of providers. Here
you have a list of all the providers available to you right now and this list
makes sense so I have a look on your own time and if you see more providers
don't worry the ones are the most important are covered in this course. So we
have AI 21 labs we have Amazon we have anthropic and so on and so we're
going to be using some of these models but the good thing about it is that when
you click on one of the provider you get a lot of information about what the
provider is so the models they have as well as some examples that you can use
with some of these models and we'll explore them very very soon and then the
types of models we have access directly from this provider as you can see for
Amazon Titan we have access to all the models right here and for each model
there's what's called a model card which explains to us what the model is
about. So about the supported formats and then some attributes some
languages that are supported and so on. If you scroll down you even get some
information about API request. So when you use Amazon bedrock right now we're
going to do everything in our browser but when you want to implement a real
application you will have to write some code and so therefore they give you some
simple code to use these specific models. So button when is Amazon bedrock
is it's super easy for you to understand how to use and select the right
models but so let's get access to some of these models and so to do so we're
going to scroll down all the way here and click on model access. So here on
this page you will conveniently see all the types of models you have access to
on AWS and to be able to use them you must first enable the models. So as you
can see right now there is all these models have are available to request some
of them can be sometimes unavailable for some reason. You can should
contact support some time and so on but we don't need access to all models but
still if you want to make this quick just click on enable all models. So here
we request access to all these models right here we're good to go just to come
next and then you need to enter some use case details around your company
name your URL and this is just some survey information it's not very very
important so enter this. So here I put Stefan Merrick and I'll put www.stefanmerrick.com
and then the industry I've operated is going to be education and then this is
for my internal employees and then it's just testing Amazon bedrock. Let's click
on next and now let's click on submit. So this doing enabling the models does
not cost any money but using the models will cost some money. So in this course I
tried to keep cost at a minimum but when you're using generative AI and AI
overall it's going to be rarely free and so therefore if you want to follow
along with me and perform the hands-on you will have to spend some money. At the
beginning of the course I gave you access to the entire budget you will have
for this course and that I've spent but it's good for you to make your own
decision. Again you cannot just also see me do and it's going to be fine. You
don't have to do everything as I do. So sometimes you will get access failed
for example these ones we cannot access to because we should talk to Amazon
support so don't worry too much about these are messages as long as you have
access to some of these models you're good to go and to get access to the models
it can take a few minutes so you can see some of them for example from Amazon
are already granted but others are in progress for example from
anthropic. And if you want to read the terms and conditions of the model you
can click here and access it. So now let me just pause this video until I get
access to all my models. Okay so it took about a minute but now as you can see
everything is access granted except the few models from Mitra and from
anthropic. Next let's go into the examples tab on the left-hand side. So now
we have access to a lot of examples that Amazon Bedrock is giving us and they're
good to explore from a learning perspective so you can explore a lot of them on
your own if you wanted to and you can filter them by provider so the ones
start for Amazon specifically and then the modality is it a text type of prompt
or is it an image type of prompt so you can do some tests. And for every prompt
right here you get access to some information so here this is a prompt to
summarize a meeting transcript into action items and you see what the prompt is
you see what the configuration was and then on the bottom you see what the
response was. So you don't have to run the examples on your own if you don't
want to you can just look at them to understand what was the prompt and what was
the response. On top of it it provides you code samples to implement this into
your own code if you need it to. So it's very handy and for example if we look
at images we can see here blue back back on the table and it generates these
kind of images. So this is cool because we can learn about AI without spending any
money but we want to actually try it out. So let's go ahead and actually explore
what's called the text playground. So here we need to first select a model so
and when you close configuration and for example we need to select a model so
I click on select model, I'll choose Amazon and then we can choose title G1
express perfect and apply. So as you can see here the throughput is on demand
that means that we're going to be paid on demand when we use the model and so
as soon as we start using them all we are going to spend some money but let's
try it out. Let's actually say what is Amazon Web Services and click on run
and now we get the response directly from the model. So here we learn about
Amazon Web Services and it's quite a detailed answer we're getting when data is
generated over time as you can see we have a lot of information given to us
by the model so we learn about overall AWS here then we learn about the
compute aspects right here then the database says right here the analytics
networking the mobile and it goes on and on and on and on so as you can see
this type of model for example gives us a very lengthy type of answer. You can
also have a look at the chat. So the chat here is again for you to select the
model. So let's take another one let's take anthropic and then we're going to
get a cloud three sonets and again I'm going to say what is AWS and we click
on run and here we get the answer directly from the model. The cool thing
about this page is that we're going to get some information around the model
metrics as well. So as you can see here the latency was seven seconds this is
number of input tokens so this is how much how much text went into the model
so 12 input tokens exactly and we see the output token counts so about 300
this is the length of the answer. So token is not exactly a word it's a bit
more complicated but this is 300 this is a pretty lengthy answer and we also
have some information around the configuration. Now this configuration we have
to look at it in greater detail later on so we need to look at it but as you
can see here I was able to ask a prompt and again I get an answer for AWS
which stands for Amazon lip services and then we get some key points about
AWS. The fact it is infrastructure as a service that has a wide range of
services we're looking at the AI ones but there's so many and so on. So as you
can see different models will give you different kind of answers and choosing
the model is going to be a big part of your work. On top of it we can put
text but we can also add files if you wanted to if the model supports it and for
image finally so here this is going to cost you a lot more money to generate
an image and to generate text so don't do it if you don't want to. We're talking
about sense but still four cents or eight cents but still it is some money. So
here's an example generate images from a prompt and we say blue backpack on the
table and we click on rent on run and we get the output of three images right
here of blue backpacks and they were fully generated by AI which is pretty
cool. So again the configurations can be pretty vast so what type of
orientation do we want? What size of the image we want? How many images do we
want and so on and so this is how to tune this image playground. But here we've
seen the basics of Amazon bedrock and chain AI so we were able to generate some
text directly using the text feature or the chat feature. We were able to
generate some images as well we're able to have a look at all the providers and
some examples associated with them and also we saw how to enable access to the
models. So that's it for the overview of Amazon bedrock. I hope you liked it
and I will see you in the next lecture.